hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
talk about ways for you to grow in your
life and in your business as a business
owner creating a mentorship coaching
training or thought leading business or
if you're an author of some kind I've
been in this industry for two decades
I've learned a thing thing or two I've
seen a thing or two I've been around the
block and
as part of my journey I had to really
make personal development a very
important part of it because I was so
focused for so long on the
strategies of what it would take to
successfully grow these businesses that
was the part that I had owned for for
two decades
was getting clients the tech
aspect uh Facebook
ads and I had to learn that when it
comes to actually building a
business it's a lot more than just what
meets the eye as far as the technical
aspects of it and there's a lot that you
need to work through as a CEO and as a
business owner and that's what I'm going
to be talking about here today is one of
those specific areas that I really had
to work through that I fought tooth and
nail and it almost you know our desire
as mentors and coaches especially if we
get into this industry and we've seen so
many
things a lot of the people that I talk
to a lot of the mentors that I talk to
have been disappointed by other mentors
and coaches they've felt let down um
maybe you're listening to this right now
and and you've felt let down by a mentor
or a coach or you've heard of other
people being let down by mentors and
coaches and and so what this does is
this creates this sort of noble desire
to not let anybody down to not
disappoint anybody to overd deliver on
everything that you say you're going to
do in your mentorship
business and I'll tell you
this that again that comes from a great
place in our heart it's a great desire
it's a nice desire um but I had to learn
that in
business and in
life I have to be okay with
disappointing people I have to be okay
with people being upset and that I can't
make it my mission to manage maintain
and control other people's emotions and
feelings because what that'll lead us to
is that'll lead us to not actually
building our business we're so focused
and concerned out how other people feel
all the time that we're not going to
build our business because here's the
thing you could do everything perfect in
your business and you're still going to
disappoint somebody now I'm not talking
about you intentionally going out there
defrauding people committing crimes
doing terrible
things and then narcissistically or
psychopathically being like hey it
doesn't matter you know I'm
disappointing people that's not what
we're talking about at all what I what
I'm talking about
is that in our our pursuit of excellence
in operating and building in a spirit of
excellence and I'd say most people who
listen to us they they resonate with the
idea of
Excellence um
even in that Pursuit you're going to
drop some balls you're going to make
mistakes you're going to let some people
down you're going to
disappoint some people and that I
believe
that being okay with disappointing other
people not being perfect soet Society
tells us we have to be
perfect and I and I and I've never been
a woman a day in my life
but I I I've been told that Society puts
a lot more pressure on women to be
perfect and I have a lot of women who
follow me and and so I I understand
there's like another layer that I've
never even
experienced to that but I also know a
lot of really sucess successful highly
successful women CEOs my mother being
one of them multi-millionaire CEO and
that she was one that that taught me
this you got to become okay with
disappointing other
people we can't let people pleasing and
other people's approval of us be the
driving
factor in our
behaviors in our business we choose see
what we want to do is we want to choose
to do as best as we can as a
choice but there comes a level of what
I've seen a spirit of Excellence that
goes into
perfectionism that then creates a
scenario where things are very very
difficult to be able to actually manage
and create the kind of results that we
want and particularly Financial results
because here's the thing as you're in
the process of building a
business of some
kind you're going to disappoint other
people it's just an irrefutable
law because and you might say no I I
won't it won't happen I it can't happen
I I will never disappoint anybody in my
business understand that that that might
again I started in that place and that's
one of the biggest things that prevented
me from making the kind of money that I
make today in my
business because I had made a commitment
to never disappoint
anybody and it's one of the biggest
things that I see that stops people from
being financially successful is this
belief and desire saying I will never
disappoint anybody and so there's
actually power in disappointing
others
and and and before you get triggered by
me saying that and I understand because
I'm I'm going against the grain of the
normal message in society right
now this is actually a message that I
had picked up from uh a lady her name is
the holistic
psychologist the holistic psychologist
nle
leera and and she was one of the first
ones who really said you know she had
she had made a post that had inspired me
it inspired my Mom this past
year I will be disappointing more people
this
year and that my her her New Year's
resolution was I will be disappointing
more people this year and I just I found
this to to resonate so much I love her
content I love her books
um particularly you know her first book
how to do the work is incredible it's
what inspired me to
actually um work with a therapist and I
worked with a therapist for for two
years straight um I just texted a
therapist uh this
week telling him you know hey I think I
think I need to have a few sessions get
back on it it's been a couple of months
seeing a few things that I that I need
to work through and and that's where I
think I think that we we have even this
stigma around therapy and mental health
and taking care of ourselves internally
when in fact that's what makes us a
powerful mentor and Coach that's what
allows us to show up at the highest
level and when you really work through
your mental
health you get to show up and say I am
who I am take it or leave it I don't
need anybody to be pleased with me I'm
okay with disappointing other people and
there's a power in that
that especially if you're operating
through the lens of delivering results
operating with excellence and
integrity you will become
Unstoppable
financially in your business when you
become okay with and you're not afraid
of other people's opinions of you
upsetting people disappointing people
people being quote unquote let down by
you is no longer the most devastating
thing that you can
experience and and and and I I find that
this is one of those
areas that it stops mentors and coaches
that they I I hear it often people say
it often I have such a fear of
disappointing others and so let's
explore that a little bit you know the
fear of disappointing others usually
comes
from a situation in our past where it
was unsafe to disappoint somebody or a
group of
somebody's any corporate job is going to
convince you to do
this um a lot of spousal
relationships even and this is an area
where I I I'm so grateful my my wife
taught me and helped and support with me
is like you're going to make mistakes
it's okay don't you don't need to beat
yourself up self-punishment I was raised
with this idea of self-loathing and
self-punishment and anytime you make a
mistake you you basically berate
yourself mentally and make yourself feel
worthless until you
know you feel the Behavior you feel like
you felt crappy enough for the behavior
to change that's what that's what I was
trained to do that's what my brain
naturally does um it happened tonight
before recording this
podcast took me a few hours to recover
to be able to record this podcast
because I was in the situ I literally
and and it was funny it happened and I
was
like literally this is an example in the
podcast I had made a
mistake in our in our house with a with
a coffee maker and we have a coffee
maker that we clean and well um if you
don't clean
it you might end up with there was there
was actually gnats that had some larvae
in the coffee maker kind of nasty it was
just in the one section that was able to
be clean but it was it was gross cuz I
had let it
go uh it was my responsibility to do and
I had let it go and and and and I knew
that that was a hot button for my wife
and it disappointed her and but it was
actually she had so much grace for me
last night with it cuz she knew I had to
record this
podcast and and and I was like I was
like honey this is a great
example but I had disappointed her I had
disappointed
myself but but the but the but the
difference is is that it was like you
know what let's let's just do better
next time and that's what my wife had
had taught me had helped me with had
worked through with me and has
encouraged me in is that you can make
mistakes it's okay to make mistakes it's
okay to mess up it's okay to make a mess
just do better next time no you we don't
need to dwell in it we don't need to sit
in it we don't need to to bathe in it
and wrap ourselves up in it we just do
better next
time and and and and I know again this
is a this is a a contrarian message to
what you might hear in a lot of other
parts of
society but what you're going to get
from me anytime I I talk with people
self-compassion not being super
self-critical Learning To Love Yourself
have compassion for the mistakes that
you make and not beating ourselves up or
pun punishing ourselves when we make
mistakes and that being healthy Behavior
to love ourselves through the
process the way the same way that I will
with my and that I do with my now
8-month-old
son is how I need to treat myself and
and there there comes a time where we
need to even
reparent ourselves in the area where our
parents might have given us one
example in our lives you know I was
talking with my with my father-in-law
about
this about a year ago you
know my parenting example and his were
very
similar I've reparented myself not him
as a father but his mother towards him
very similar to my mother in some areas
that you know him and I both would see
are not a healthy way of parenting but
it helps shape the Two of Us in in the
way that we are today and we both
recognize that and the value in
it but the reparenting is what I think
has helped me become so much more
powerful so much more have so much more
to
offer have so
much uh that I've been able to create in
my business is through that reparenting
and being o okay
with disappointing other people
disappointing
myself not that I seek out opportunities
to disappoint myself for other people my
goodness no but it's just like we let go
of that added pressure of I need to do
everything perfect in our lives and my
wife and I we found that like by doing
that and I would say the most successful
people my
mother and and I talk about this all the
time that like her financial success
came from letting go of needing
everything to be perfect she used to be
so OCD obsessive about the house being
perfect growing up and and she looks
back and she's like I would never have
been that way anymore
like you know and so it's it's
incredible that every financially
successful person that I know has this
Revelation that we just got to let go of
perfectionism we got to let go of the
the crown of doing everything perfect
managing other people having all the
puzzle pieces perfectly balanced in our
life and realize that actually chaos is
part of life and and that that there's
no perfect moment to do anything now
there's no perfect time to get started
with anything just like there's no
perfect time to get into a relationship
there's no perfect time to invest in the
stock market there's no perfect time to
invest in real estate you might be
hearing me saying that saying wait
Jeremiah what are you talking about real
estate in the stock market there's
perfect no there's
not and those are principle you know my
mom she mentors people on investing
that's a principle of successful
investing up and down Market you want to
be in the market you want to be
consistent we can't wait until
everything is perfect and work so hard
to try to avoid disappointing other
people and things not going how what's
inside of our
control so much we can't control other
people no matter how hard we
try and no matter what you do you're
going to have somebody who is ultimately
disappointed and so you might as well
just give up trying to be perfect not
upset people not disappoint
people and just be you just do you just
do what you want to
do and build the business of your
dreams go out there and be confident I
hear people say this all the time they
won't launch their mentorship program
because they're afraid it's going to
disappoint other
people it might disappoint
somebody then what why is that so bad
what's so terrible about
that and you might be hearing that
saying questioning my ethics and morals
around that listen I I tell you I filter
this
through giving it my best focused on
creating results for my clients yall
know in this in my mentorship
program I'm making this like I'm
speaking to my mentorship program y'all
aren't even this is a free piece of
content right here but those that are in
my paid mentorship program
know that I go above and beyond to
deliver results for our
clients
but I but I but I
don't I don't make avoiding
disappointing other people be the
driving factor of it and when I gave up
that Crown that's what allowed me to
start and build a business that in the
last 12 months has done seven figures
because I wasn't afraid of disappointing
other people it's one of the one of the
greatest areas in my life that I think
has contributed to my own financial
success is every single time that I stop
worrying about disappointing other
people my income
increases because what I start doing is
I start prioritizing putting the pieces
in order in the way that's going to
serve my life my business and the vision
that I have for my life because I'm not
trying to juggle how other people feel
around
me and so
so this is one of the single greatest
areas if you can get this and you and
you legitimately like hold it and and
you can
say and believe I'm okay with
disappointing other
people and you qu and you ask yourself
why is that so difficult to say figure
out what's underneath the surface that's
going to be a real indicator for you of
what what's underneath the surface to
learn and to discover a what you don't
know and B what you can learn about
yourself by seeing okay why is this
quote unquote so
triggering overall this idea that I just
I I can't disappoint other people why is
the idea of disappointing others so tra
magic for
us and start to question where that
teaching came in start to
question who influenced us to not make
ourselves a priority to tell our to tell
us that that's wrong and selfish and
even evil or Wicked or or whatever that
is where did that influence come
from this idea that we have to be
perfect and can't disappoint
anybody it's not
healthy it's not rooted in in in in in
anything that's going to serve us again
it might come from a a nice place but
overall it's hurting us in the
end and so again it might not happen
overnight but I would encourage
you prioritize the life you want to
create create for yourself the vision
that you have for your life even if it
disappoints other people even if they
tell you you shouldn't be doing that
thing even if they tell you you
shouldn't be going down that
path you know it's funny what I just
told
you as grown adults is a very healthy
thing you know if I told that to my my
eight-month-old or a three-year-old like
that would make sense
right he needs to listen to what we tell
him to do as adults this is where we re
we activate ourselves and we reparent
ourselves and we we we give ourselves
permission to do what we couldn't do
when we were younger or what we couldn't
do inside of a corporate job and this is
why as a CEO in a business see that's
the difference in your own business
all responsibility falls on you and so
no matter what you do right there's
always going to be somebody who
disppointed and some people use
disappointment as a form of manipulation
by the
way some people use that I'm so
disappointed as a way to try to get
their way and control and manipulate
other people because they know that
people are so afraid of disappointing
others see that's what it is and I'm and
I and and and that ends up happening
there's people I've met that are like
that is they knew that I was afraid of
disappointing people so they used that
to twist me to control me to do things I
didn't want to
do and so if we be if we're so worried
about disappointing other people and we
and we are so afraid of making other
people
unhappy we become easy to manipulate we
become easy
targets of somebody who who is a
manipulator and so you can see even the
benefit of our own safety to not get
manipulated into doing things I used to
get manipulated into doing things that I
didn't want to do because I got around
some really nasty people that took
advantage of my wanting other people's
approval and not disappointing others
and I look back to this day it's
actually one of the biggest it's one of
the reasons I went to I went to
jail you know I had a guy
he he he dared me and I was afraid of
disappointing him and so I did the Dare
and the Dare was what got me put in
jail cuz I was afraid of disappointing
him so you see how like this
extrapolates out to like really
unhealthy Behavior at that point like
that's an extreme level but that same
thing stops us from building our
business stops us from asking for the
sale because we we want to be nice and
kind and not upset people and all that
and and it's like at the point of when
you're asking for the sale people are
ready to hear an
offer we can't let the fear of people
being mad at us and disappointed in US
stop us from being successful and listen
the Judgment that you might have on
other people who have disappointed you
you might need to let that go
well I would never be the way that they
are I would never do the things that
they would do I was so disappointed and
let down by them I would never do the
thing that they have done to
me and that's one of the worst mindsets
that we can get
into is where we end up fully projecting
and changing the behaviors of our life
and our business through our through an
unhealed wound of how some somebody else
had hurt
us and so there's so much benefit to
healing in this area to growing in this
area to be to
becoming
stronger in this area instead of just
letting our fears and our
worries guide and direct
us we decide Hey
listen
I'm going to do my very best but if but
if other people are not happy with me
that's okay I'm going to continue doing
what I know is best and I'm going to
continue going down a path even if I
have people telling me that I should
stop because they don't like what I'm
doing and that behavior as a CEO that
that makes you
Unstoppable that makes you to where you
can go out there and and create the life
you want some of
us are in an environment right
now where we have people that are
disappointed in US constantly and we're
constantly put in situations of
disappointing other people and we're
around critical people whether it be at
a job a
workplace customers of a workplace that
you work
at a boss a spouse a
church it's a big
one and so we have to decide okay wait a
sec I want you to look at anybody in
your life who's constantly telling you
how wrong you are about things that you
do they're constantly criticizing and
telling you how like and and it's not
it's it's not in a loving way and they
might be saying it's for your own good
but they're just they're very critical
of you all the time you're not going to
change that person that's their nature
so we got to just accept that that's how
they are let that go but start to limit
how much you take in what they
say that's a choice that we can make is
to limit how much we take especially if
we have to work with them on a
consistent basis especially if it's a
spouse I'm not you
know there's a way to
where we don't take in the criticism and
we don't let it spiral us out of control
it's that
point the it's better to limit your
exposure to that type of person but if
you
can't as you grow in your own mental
fortitude and your own mental strength
you can actually get to the point where
that type of person's no longer going to
to have as much of an effect on you at
that point and that's where I've gotten
to now and and and that's why I can
recover so quickly to be able to do a
podcast like this immediately after a
situation that would have just
completely derailed me for an entire day
or so at that I mean that was that was a
big deal that happened this evening but
I didn't get derailed I knew I had to
make this podcast I knew I had to
connect with people I knew I had to
create this and I couldn't let
disappointing myself or others or any
type of situation stop me from doing the
thing that I needed to do in my business
creating this
podcast and that's the type of behavior
that I want to encourage you to get
to it'll change your life it'll change
everything about your life because
you're not going to be afraid
of things going wrong making a mess them
not being perfect people being upset
with
you nasty emails from
people we can't let the fear of
disappointing
others control control us it used to
control me for years and I found power
in accepting and being okay with
disappointing other people not doing
everything perfectly and just being
myself and that's what helped my
business grow and so I hope that this
has encouraged you I hope that this has
given you some food for thought some
ideas that you can learn from share with
other people this might be a paradigm
shift for you you might need to relist
to this podcast episode a few times to
start to get it inside of you and to
start to even process through some of
those triggers if you maybe felt
triggered listening through this
processing through those as you listen
again and again and again well actually
then it could be a healing exercise for
you by listening to this podcast episode
but listen if this has helped you don't
just keep it to yourself share this
podcast with somebody share this with
somebody that you know that it's going
top positively impact
them I'm so thankful for you all that
listen to this and if you haven't joined
us for one of our live training events
that we're doing we help mentors
trainers coaches and thought leaders
grow their businesses create massive
amounts of impact and income in their
life and in their business and so that's
the goal of this podcast it's a free
resource that I put out there because I
know that free resources help people
it's my way of giving back and it also
helps me tell people about the different
things that we have to offer join us for
one of our free live events if you're
not in my client growth accelerator
group mentorship program where I'm
helping mentors and coaches grow their
businesses get on the waiting list for
it jump in when we open the doors next
to it and I don't know when that's going
to be but you'll be the first to
know and and I'll talk soon everybody
grow your life have a good
one
[Music]
[Applause]